

Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/lbsa71

Email: lbsa71@hotmail.com Phone: +46-733 75 11 99

Languages

English: Bilingual Swedish: Native

Links

https://lbsa71.net https://soundcloud.com/lbsa71 https://github.com/lbsa71

This CV generated with https://github.com/lbsa71/cv

Stefan Andersson

Jack of all IT trades, master of quite a few

Professional Summary

With 35+ years of experience across many tech stacks and organizational levels, Stefan has become a founder's Swiss army knife - a one-man matrix organization. His versatility spans strategic vision to tactical execution, making him the ideal cornerstone hire for ambitious initiatives and emerging ventures

Professional Experience

Full Stack Developer (Apr 2024 - Dec 2024)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Sweden

I was part of developing https://hiber3d.com/ Game Studio, SDK, tool chain, backend services and example apps; as a senior resource I coded, created full-stack 3D Web game demos in React and C++, tested, deployed and maintained the entire Hiber3D offer from a technical angle.

Key Skills: Amazon Web Services (AWS) • AWS Aurora • AWS DocumentDB • C++ • CI/CD • DevOps • Docker • Firebase • Firestore • Full-Stack Development • GCP Cloud Build • GitHub Actions • Google Cloud Platform (GCP) • GraphQL • Infrastructure as code (IaC) • Next.js • Python • React Native • React • Serverless • Terraform Cloud • Terraform Script • TypeScript

Systems Administrator (Oct 2020 - Dec 2024)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Sweden

As their CTO I took a hands-on approach to make sure that IT systems were properly managed, managing onboarding/offboarding, billing, cost and securing their systems. When I stepped aside, I offered to continue the admin role to offload my successor. I also functioned as the main resource for security policy and training.

Key Skills: Backoffice IT Management • CI/CD • Google Cloud Platform (GCP) • Google Workspace • Infrastructure as code (IaC) • Security • Terraform Cloud • Terraform Script

Al Software Developer (Jun 2023 - Apr 2024)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Sweden

As lead for the Hiber AI Research initiative I led the effort to build and host various large and small multimodal generative AI toolchains. I got to work with a plethora of third-party APIs as well as training, deploying and managing models on GCP Compute and Vertex AI

Key Skills: Amazon Web Services (AWS) • CI/CD • DevOps • Docker • Fine Tuning • Firestore • Full-Stack Development • GCP Cloud Build • GitHub Actions • Google Cloud Platform (GCP) • Large Language Models (LLM) • Next.js • Node.js • Prompt Engineering • Python • React • Terraform Cloud • Terraform Script • Vector Databases

React / TypeScript Developer (Oct 2022 - Oct 2023)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Sweden

As a member of the Platform team I worked as a full stack developer; IAC, DevOps, CI, CD, Databases, Backends, Frontend, Multiple Build Chains, Package Management, Automatic testing.

Key Skills: Amazon Web Services (AWS) • App Center • AWS Aurora • CI/CD • CSS • Docker • Expo • Firebase • Firestore • Full-Stack Development • GitHub Actions • Infrastructure as code (IaC) • Next.js • Node.js • React Native • React • Tailwind CSS • Terraform Cloud • Terraform Script • TypeScript

Information Security | Test Automation Lead (Jan 2022 - Jul 2022)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Sweden

In this period Hiber did a push to formalize their security compliance and test automation policy. I was the lead for both these projects, making sure to always properly manage risk and cost.

Key Skills: Test Automation • CI/CD • Software Project Management • Security • Compliance

Chief Technology Officer (Oct 2020 - Dec 2021)

Hiber | Gothenburg, Sweden

Hiber is a venture-backed startup with headquarters in Gothenburg, Sweden, focused on building a social platform for anyone to communicate and express themselves through game-like experiences. As their CTO I organised technology and four agile teams to deliver success while growing.

Key Skills: Agile Methodologies • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • App Center • AWS Aurora • Business Strategy • CI/CD • CSS • Docker • Expo • Firebase • Firestore • Full-Stack Development • Infrastructure as code (IaC) • Next.js • Node.js • React Native • React • React • Software Project Management • Tailwind CSS • Team Leadership • Terraform Cloud • Terraform Script • TypeScript

CISO | Product Owner | Business Analyst | CloudOps Engineer | Systems Developer (Apr 2018 - Oct 2020)

Allevi AB | Gothenburg, Sweden

Allevi AB is the premium provider of time management for LSS, HVB and LOV care providers in Sweden. The company is highly driven by humane values and implements an 'making a difference' ethos supporting independent living. As their CISO, I made sure they and their customers were kept safe and as a CloudOps engineer I made sure they could deliver highly available systems cost effectively.

Key Skills: Amazon Web Services (AWS) • AWS CloudFormation • CI/CD • Compliance • DevOps • Full-Stack Development • Infrastructure as code (IaC) • MySQL • PHP • Product Management • Security • Software Project Management • Symphony • Test Automation

Senior Software Developer at Saab (Apr 2017 - Mar 2018)

Acorn Technology AB | Gothenburg, Sweden

I helped the Secure Transportation team develop the Track and Trace product suite that provide customers with a secure logistic solution for different kinds of transportation. With this solution a user can gain full control over their logistic services through a work-order based system that manages, monitors and measures all services provided for the end customer. The system also creates an operational audit trail from commitment start to final execution, which facilitates having full control throughout the entire transport logistics chain.

Senior Technical Consultant (Feb 2016 - Mar 2018)

Acorn Technology AB | Gothenburg, Sweden

What attracted me with the young consultancy firm Acorn was that they are committed to nurture a culture in which capable individuals can grow. The decision to leave did not come easy, and I recommend them whole-heartedly both as employers and as suppliers of .NET, Java and embedded software development talent.

Key Skills: Full-Stack Development • C# • Microsoft.NET

Lead Developer at Aros Electronics AB (Feb 2017 - Mar 2017)

Acorn Technology AB | Gothenburg, Sweden

I was brought in to help Aros bootstrap development of the control system for testing and programming stations in their automated circuit board production facility. The assignment also consisted of coaching the inhouse developers on modern .NET development practices and Software Architecture.

Key Skills: Full-Stack Development • C# • Microsoft.NET • Mechatronics

Senior Developer Team Lead at KGH Customs Services (Feb 2016 - Jan 2017)

Acorn Technology AB | Gothenburg, Sweden

KGH Customs services is a premiere provider of customs services. Central to these services is the software-as-a-service web based logistics center, integrating KGH, customers and international customs. My role was as Senior Developer and Team Lead for the feature team developing automation of customs declarations, an I also served as the Architect and principal developer for their schema-driven UI Framework.

Key Skills: Full-Stack Development • Software Architecture • Microsoft SQL Server • CI/CD • C# • JavaScript • Microsoft.NET • RabbitMQ

Senior Software Architect | Senior Software Developer | Lead Tech (Mar 2009 - Feb 2016)

TIBCO Spotfire | Gothenburg, Sweden

TIBCO Spotfire is the premier studio for enterprise-scale Interactive Visual Analytics. Solutions and Software Architect, Senior Systems Developer and Lead Tech for https://spotfire.cloud.tibco.com/ 1.0.0, 3.0.0-3.3.0 https://silverspotfire.tibco.com/ 2.0-2.7 https://tryspotfire.tibco.com/ 2.0-2.7 Project manager for https://silverspotfire.tibco.com/ 2.0-2.1.1

Key Skills: Full-Stack Development • AngularJS • Microsoft.NET • Microsoft SQL Server • MySQL • CI/CD • Java • C# • Software Architecture • Product Management

Co-founder | Lead Programmer (Jan 2007 - Oct 2009)

OpenSim | Gothenburg, Sweden

The OpenSimulator Project is a BSD Licensed Virtual Worlds Server which can be used for creating and deploying 3D Virtual Environments. Fun fact: the platform is mentioned in David Chalmers "Reality+"

Key Skills: Full-Stack Development • Microsoft SQL Server • MySQL • C# • Open Source

CEO (Apr 2007 - Mar 2009)

Tribal Media AB | Gothenburg, Sweden

Tribal Media AB created high quality high technology interactive 3D mass media solutions.

Key Skills: Software Project Management • Team Leadership • Product Management

Senior Developer | Tech Lead (Apr 2007 - Mar 2009)

Tribal Media AB |

Architected and Developed TribalOne, a first-generation distributed 3D Web Metaverse application platform.

Lead Programmer (Aug 2004 - Apr 2007)

Playahead AB | Helsingborg, Skåne County, Sweden

Playahead was Swedens second largest youth web community.

CTO (May 2001 - Jun 2003)

Voice Workers AB | Gothenburg, Sweden

Voice Workers produced speech recognition and natural dialogue management solutions for telephony.

Key Skills: Full-Stack Development • Java • Interactive Voice Response (IVR) • Natural Language Processing (NLP) • Team Leadership

CTO | Senior consultant (Apr 2000 - Mar 2001)

Ullman Human Design Group AB | Gothenburg, Sweden

I helped bring the 'Ullman Mouse' into existence by choosing their USB controller and coding assembler for it.

Key Skills: Assembly Language • Team Leadership

Lead Programmer | Software Architect | Key Account Manager (Apr 1998 - Dec 1999)

Framfab | Gothenburg, Sweden

Framfab was the second largest web consultancy in Sweden.

Key Skills: Full-Stack Development • Software Architecture

Notable Projects

TIBCO Spotfire® Cloud 1.0.0 (Aug 2012 - Present)

TIBCO Spotfire® Cloud 3.0.0 (Aug 2014 - Dec 2014)

Zero Audience (Aug 2019 - Present)

Zero Audience is a pop-up DJ collective, bringing music to the public space by making bystanders participants.

DJ St. Éphan (Jul 2018 - Present)

Loving music, I also love to play music. Under the moniker St. Éphan I have played in several settings and taught 150+ people the basics of digital beatmixing. Most of my sets available at https://lbsa71.net

Education

University of Gothenburg

Bachelor of Science 1996 - 2015

I started my IT studies in 1996, got swept up by the web and finally made it back to take my degree 20 years later.

University of Gothenburg

Courses

1995 - 1996

I took one year of intermediate psychology studies which gave me valuable insights about myself, the work I do, and the world I live in.

Dale Carnegie

2012 - 2013

Course in Communication and Leadership

Technical Skills

Cloud & Infrastructure

AWS Aurora • AWS CloudFormation • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • DevOps • GCP Cloud Build • GitHub Actions • Google Cloud Platform (GCP) • Infrastructure as code (IaC) • RabbitMQ • Serverless • Terraform Cloud

Databases

AWS DocumentDB • Firestore • GraphQL • Microsoft SQL Server • MySQL

Programming Languages

Assembly Language • C# • C++ • CSS • Java • JavaScript • PHP • Python • Tailwind CSS • Terraform Script • TypeScript

Core Competencies

Backoffice IT Management • CI/CD • Full-Stack Development • Interactive Voice Response (IVR) • Mechatronics • Natural Language Processing (NLP) • Test Automation

Frameworks

AngularJS • Docker • Firebase • Microsoft.NET • Mono • Next.js • Node.js • React • React Native • Symphony

Tools

App Center • Expo • Google Workspace

Engineering Practices

Compliance • Open Source • Security • Software Architecture

Artificial Intelligence

Fine Tuning • Large Language Models (LLM) • Prompt Engineering • Vector Databases

Management

Agile Methodologies • Business Strategy • Product Management • Software Project Management • Team Leadership